<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>[XND] Vanilla-Friendly Animal Surgery (Continued)</name>
  <packageId>Mlie.XNDVanillaFriendlyAnimalSurgery</packageId>
  <author>XeoNovaDan</author>
  <url>https://github.com/emipa606/XNDVanillaFriendlyAnimalSurgery</url>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.0</li>
    <li>1.1</li>
    <li>1.2</li>
    <li>1.3</li>
    <li>1.4</li>
    <li>1.5</li>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <description>[img]https://i.imgur.com/buuPQel.png[/img]
Update of XeoNovaDan mod
https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1130112804

- Replaced the patches with assemblies instead, should now work on all animals similar to [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2270547158][XND] Animal Armor (Continued)[/url]
- Added the possibility to craft all animal body-parts
- Added ear implants

[img]https://i.imgur.com/pufA0kM.png[/img]

[table]
    [tr]
        [td][url=https://dsc.gg/mlie][img]https://i.imgur.com/zdzzBrc.png[/img][/url][/td]
        [td][url=https://github.com/emipa606/XNDVanillaFriendlyAnimalSurgery][img]https://i.imgur.com/kTkpTOE.png[/img][/url][/td]
    [/tr]
    [tr]
        [td][img]https://i.imgur.com/WjDSfUn.png[/img][/td]
        [td][img]https://i.imgur.com/Be8E2qJ.png[/img][/td]
    [/tr]
[/table]
	
[img]https://i.imgur.com/Z4GOv8H.png[/img]

[strike][h1][b]Compatibility[/b][/h1]
For Modders: To make a patch for this mod, simply plug the defNames of your mod&amp;apos;s animals into the appropriate XML patches. Vanilla animal patches can be found in Patches/Core for reference.[/strike]

I wouldn&amp;apos;t recommend using this [i]and[/i] &amp;apos;A Dog Said&amp;apos; together due to the overlap of parts and balance inconsistencies that will be introduced.

Recommended to use with [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2270547158][b]Animal Armor[/b][/url] to maximize the customization of your animals.

[strike]No animal mods have been made compatible with this yet. I&amp;apos;m not going to be responsible for creating compatibility patches with other mods either.[/strike]

[h1][b]Overview[/b][/h1]
For those that still want animal surgery in the game but don&amp;apos;t like the &amp;apos;one size fits all&amp;apos; philosophy of A Dog Said (e.g. the same bionic part fitting on a squirrel that also fits on an elephant).

Vanilla-Friendly Animal Surgery adds the following body parts for animals: dentures; peg legs; hearts; kidneys; lungs; livers; simple prosthetic arms; simple prosthetic legs; bionic arms; bionic eyes; bionic legs and painstoppers. Dentures and peg legs are installed on animals in the same way that you&amp;apos;d install them on a colonist in vanilla RimWorld.

Similarly, larger parts are going to be more powerful than their smaller brethren: a small bionic leg might do 8 damage if installed frontally, but a large one will do 15.

These are the five size categories:
[b]Tiny -[/b] Fits on animals with a mature body size of less than 0.3, such as chickens and squirrels.
[b]Small -[/b] Fits on animals with a mature body size between 0.3 and 0.7, such as monkeys and alphabeavers.
[b]Medium -[/b] Fits on animals with a mature body size between 0.7 and 1.3, such as boars and ostriches.
[b]Large -[/b] Fits on animals with a mature body size between 1.3 and 2.4, such as muffalo and bears.
[b]Huge -[/b] Fits on animals with a mature body size equal to or greater than 2.4, such as rhinoceroses and thrumbos.

[strike]Animal organs and prostheses, similar to human prostheses in the base game, can only be obtained via trade; you can&amp;apos;t produce them or expect them to come falling from the sky. For balance reasons and due to XML limitations, you can&amp;apos;t harvest animals for their organs either; they also can only be obtained via trade.[/strike]

Animal body parts also have their own trade categories, so these won&amp;apos;t interfere with the commonality of human body parts on the market. Additionally, adding part to and removing parts from animals only yields 5/16ths as much experience as an operation on a human, to reduce the feasibility of experience grinding.

[h1][b]Credits[/b][/h1]
Marnador for their excellent RimWorld-style font.
Shotgunfrenzy for the &amp;apos;Combat Extended Compatible&amp;apos; text on the thumbnail.

[h1][b]License[/b][/h1]
You may use this mod in your mod packs, and you may also derive from the mod. All that I ask is that you please let me know, and give me credit and provide a link to this mod&amp;apos;s forum post.

[img]https://i.imgur.com/PwoNOj4.png[/img]
[list]
[*] See if the the error persists if you just have this mod and its requirements active.
[*] If not, try adding your other mods until it happens again.
[*] Post your error-log using [url=https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=818773962]HugsLib[/url] or the standalone [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2873415404]Uploader[/url] and command Ctrl+F12
[*] For best support, please use the Discord-channel for error-reporting.
[*] Do not report errors by making a discussion-thread, I get no notification of that.
[*] If you have the solution for a problem, please post it to the GitHub repository.
[*] Use [url=https://github.com/RimSort/RimSort/releases/latest]RimSort[/url] to sort your mods
[/list] 

[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/changelog/2343960451][img]https://img.shields.io/github/v/release/emipa606/XNDVanillaFriendlyAnimalSurgery?label=latest%20version&amp;style=plastic&amp;color=9f1111&amp;labelColor=black[/img][/url] | tags:  prosthetics,  bionics</description>
  <modVersion IgnoreIfNoMatchingField="True">1.6.0</modVersion>
</ModMetaData>